Shivam Kumar

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India



shivam.kumar110@gmail.com



+919886516124



linkedin.com/in/shivamkumar1100

Summary

I am a Computer Science & Engineering Graduate from one of India's premier institutes i.e. Indian Institute of Infomation Technology, Design & Manufacturing.

I have a keen interest in Design, and Software Development, hence I developed skills in Design(Adobe Suite) And front-end technologies like Javascript, React, and Vue.

In my career of 5+ years, I have built projects from scratch which now serve 1000s of people/customers, and the number is still growing.

Right now I am leading a team of size 5 including 3 developers and 2 QAs, handling all aspects including Backend, Frontend, and QA.

I love watching Sitcoms, Space, and History documentaries in my free time.

Experience



Technical Lead

Capiter

Jun 2022 - Present (6 months +)

Leading a team of 5 people including 3 developers and 2 QAs for a B2B product for sellers called Marketplace.

Responsibilities:

- Delivered the very first version of the B2B marketplace app.
- Design and Architect backend APIs and UI Components for higher scalability and performance.
- Deliverables and Sprint Planning
- Finalisation of UX with the Design Team

Tech: Javascript, Angular 12, MySQL, Kubernetes, CLK Stack, Prometheus.

Member Of Technical Staff - 3

Nutanix

Nov 2020 - May 2022 (1 year 7 months)

One of the core members of the DRaaS(Disaster Recovery as a Service) team, which handles the core data Recovery process of Nutanix-based systems.

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for end-to-end feature development.
- Optimization and technical detailing.
- Discuss and finalize the APIs contract with Backend.
- Improved overall code quality by writing Unit Tests and keeping code coverage >95%

Tech: Javascript, ReactJS, Redux, Less, NodeJS Unit Testing: JestJS, Enzyme, React Testing Library

Tools: JIRA, Git, Webpack, VSCode, NPM, ESLint

Software Engineer

COVIAM

Jul 2017 - Oct 2020 (3 years 4 months)

Worked in the teams for various Supply Chain Management Apps/ Tools for the Indonesian e-commerce platform Blibli.com.

Responsibilities:

- Built and Architect App from scratch.
- Lead and work with a team of 2-3 UI devs.
- Discuss and finalize APIs contract with Backend.
- Solve business problems and add features for them.
- Solved two big problems like scheduling and efficiency in Logistics and Warehouse App by using viable solution front-end techs.
- Improve overall code quality by writing Unit Tests and keeping code coverage >95%
- Train Interns in front-end techs like ReactJS, VueJS, Jest, etc.

Techs: Javascript, ReactJS, Redux, VueJS, Vuex, SCSS, HTML

Unit Testing: JestJS, KarmaJS, ChaiJS

Tools: JIRA, Git, Webpack, VSCode, NPM, Yarn, ESLint

Projects Worked On:

1. Transportation Management System (Logistics App)

Responsible for the development of the end-to-end features. It's a system that handles the logistics part from pickup to delivery.

Tech: ReactJS, Redux, Javascript, SCSS, Webpack

2. Lead Tracking System (B2B Marketplace)

Architect and built the app from scratch. It's a B2B marketplace that enables merchants to connect with BliBli and conduct business all in one place.

Tech: ReactJS, Redux, Javascript, HTML, SCSS, Webpack

3. Fulfilled By Blibli

Architect and built the app from scratch. It's a service that provides storage, packaging, and shipping assistance to sellers.

Tech: VueJS, Vuex, Javascript, SCSS, Webpack, Axios, Jest

4. Inventory Management System

Architect and built the app from scratch. Its a system for tracking inventory levels, orders, sales, and deliveries

Tech: VueJS, Vuex, Javascript, SCSS, Webpack, Jest

5. Inventory Planning System

Architect and built the app from scratch. It is an app to decide the optimal quantity as well as timing, with the sole aim of aligning such plans with the organization's capacity.

Tech: VueJS, Vuex, Javascript, SCSS, Webpack, KarmaJS

Education



闭 Indian Institute of Information Technology, Design and Manufacturing, Jabalpur

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Computer Science 2013 - 2017

Licenses & Certifications



HTML Expert - Score 95% - mypath io



in Svelte: First Look - LinkedIn

Skills

AngularJS • Java • React.js • Vue.js • Javascript • User Experience (UX) • Jest • Unit Testing • Webpack • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)

Honors & Awards



Second Runner Up - CODIECON 2019 - COVIAM

Mar 2019

Won the second runner up prize for making a smart city app in CODIECON 2019, organized by Coviam Technologies from 9-11 March 2019, in which 50+ teams participated at Bengaluru.